ANTHONY GORDON KRUGER

• DETAILS •

0610340820 antman.kruger@gmail.com

○ LINKS ○

Linkedin

GitHub

o SKILLS o

PHP
HTML5

CSS

JavaScript

jQuery

Java

Python

C#

C++

VB.net

Wordpress

Linux/Unix

SQL

• LANGUAGES •

Microsoft as an OS

Afrikaans

PROFILE

I am keen to fulfil my dreams to become a software developer and pivot my career into information technology for which I have finished my bachelor's degree in information technology in 2021. As an accomplished Retail Branch manager my management skills and sales experience will be of great value to my future employer. The ideal opportunity would be where I can leverage my interaction skills, operational experience, and positive attitude. It will also provide me with the opportunity to enhance my creativity and acquire new skills.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Freelance Web Developer / Systems Administrator at DPTS pty ltd, International

November 2020 — Present

I am leading a web development team that build dynamic websites and ecommerce stores for international clients of DPTS. This includes migration of code and parameters to the quality assurance and production environments. Also, I am further responsible for the administration and support of the cloud hosted environments on Microsoft Azure for DPTS and its' clients. This includes selecting and setting optimal servers up for use as web and back-office servers for the e-commerce and CRM applications, including ensuring that servers and data are secured and backed up frequently. Working with international clients has also broadened my horizon and understanding of diverse client needs. This experience has allowed me to gain handson experience to complement the theoretical knowledge obtained as I complete my three-year bachelor's degree in information technology.

Branch Manager at The Lighting Warehouse, Pretoria

June 2018 — Present

Directing all operational aspects including distribution, customer service, human resources, administration and sales in accordance with the company's objectives. Providing training, coaching, development and motivation for branch personnel. Developing forecasts and financial objectives.

Sales Manager at The Lighting Warehouse, Pretoria

August 2016 — May 2018

Achieving growth and hitting sales targets by successfully managing the sales team. Designing and implementing a strategic sales plan that expands company's customer base and ensure it's strong presence.

Sales Consultant at The Lighting Warehouse, Pretoria

June 2014 — July 2016

Develop and attain customer experience and sales objectives for store. Sell all products and services offered by the Company. Meet all sales objectives. Maintain strong knowledge of all products, accessories, pricing plans, promotions and service features. Maintain knowledge of competitive offers and provide critical market feedback to the Store Manager regarding local competition and product/service needs. Handle service inquiries from customers. Provide efficient, courteous customer service and assist in all aspects of product offerings and services. Ensure an extraordinary customer experience.

Administrator at Precision Financial Services, Pretoria

January 2014 — April 2014

Responsible for consulting with new clients, liaising with clients telephonically, replying to inquiries, day to day data capturing and emailing clients.

Sales Representative at Bullion: The Gold Buying Company, Pretoria

October 2013 — December 2013

Responsible for attracting clients, demonstrating company services through various sales techniques, buying of gold in a public environment.

Sales representative & assistant at Gutpel Distributors, Pretoria

July 2021 — July 2021

Responsible for exposure of multiple products to the public (delivering of the various products and updating clients on regular basis).

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree in Information Technology , Richfield Graduate Institute of Technology, Pretoria

January 2019 — December 2021

Bachelor of science in information technology specializing in Systems Development.

 $\textbf{6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, MiTx, Online } \\ \textbf{August 2018} \\ \textbf{-November 2018}$

online certificate link:

https://courses.edx.org/certificates/4a21f40f94dc4d5da93426422982fc1b

6.00.2x Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science, MiTx, Online

November 2018 — December 2018

Online certificate:

https://courses.edx.org/certificates/fa03b6b8c0a04312945e938093948cd2

level 1 First aid, Nosa, Pretoria

August 2018 — August 2018

Level 1 first aid training.

National Senior Certificate, Lyttleton Manor, Pretoria

January 2006 — December 2010

- o National Senior Certificate December 2010
- o Half colours for academics

1 REFERENCES

Johan Kruger from Digital and Payments Transformation Services

jk.kruger@dpts.co.za · 082 497 7410

Dylan Park from The Lighting Warehouse

dylan@lightingwarehouse.co.za · 079 695 1792

Linnet Adams from Precision Financial Services

linneta@mumbi.co.za · 012 655 0618

Donald from Bullion: The Gold Buying Company

078 776 7609

Christopher Gutwies from Gutpel Distributors

082 573 1909